In this video, I'll be talking about operators.
I'll be discussing what operators are, going over arithmetic operators and logical and relational
operators.
Operators are used to perform calculations and comparisons.
Here's some examples.
We have a lesson operator, and we have a subtraction operator.
Operators work on operands.
Here we have an example.
We have the plus operator, and it's operating on the operands A and B.
Here's a listing of the arithmetic operators that are available within Go.
We have addition, which is plus subtraction as a minus, multiplication as a star, division
as a forward slash, and remainder division is a percent symbol.
You'll see on the right here we have the operators and an equal sign, and what that does
is it takes an existing variable performs this operation and reassigns the result to that
variable.
You'll see that align code that you can use that to increment numbers or add some value
to an existing variable.
Let's take a look at how to use some operators.
For using arithmetic operators, here we're creating a variable named total, and we're just
using three plus three.
Our operator here is plus, our operands are three and three, and that'll be assigned
to six, and it'll be placed into the total variable.
To use arithmetic assignment, here we're creating variable A, setting it to the value
of one.
We're using plus equals with three, and so that will take the existing A, and add three
to it, and then A will now be equal to four.
And that's the same as doing A equals A plus three, so this is a shortcut for doing that.
We also have increment and decrement operators, so these are very common in loops.
Here we have a variable I, and if we do plus plus, we're just going to be adding one
to the I, and if we do minus minus, we're going to be subtracting one from the I.
Whenever you're working with arithmetic operators, it's always going to be returning
a number, so you're not going to get any errors or any strings back.
You're always going to get a number that you're working with.
Let's take a look at the relational operators.
We have less than, less than or equal to greater than, greater than or equal to, equal
to, and finally, not equal to.
Relational operators always return a Boolean, so whenever you're using, in this example,
greater than, and also equal to, you're always going to get either true or false back.
So in this case, if A is bigger than B, because we're doing greater than, then that would
be true, and if X was equal to Y, that would also be true.
The X is equal to Y case.
If they're not equal, then you're going to get a false, and in the A greater than B, if
A is, for example, zero and B is two, then you're going to get a false back on that one.
Now we'll take a look at some logic operators.
We have an, which is two ampersands, or which is two bars.
The bars are above the enter key below the backspace on most keyboards, and we also have
not, which is an exclamation point, and that'll invert a value.
So let's take a look at how to use those.
So what you can do with the logic operators is combine true and false things.
So in this example, we have, these would all be Booleans, so we have authorized and authenticated.
So both of these need to be true, because we're using two ampersands.
So both of those are true, then the return value will also be true.
If either one of these is false, then the return value will be false.
Here we're using Or with the two bars.
So if we have red or blue, if either one of these is true, so if red is true and blue
is false, we're still going to get a true back, and that's because we're using Or.
So we only need one of these things, and there could be a, there could be a menu you
can keep going with as many as you want.
If any one of those is true, then you're going to get a true back.
And with the exclamation point, you're going to invert whatever you have.
So if heavy is true, once you apply the exclamation point, it's now going to be false.
Let's recap, operators operate on operands, arithmetic operators enable calculations, arithmetic
assignment can calculate and assign to a variable in a single statement, relational operators
enable comparisons, and logic operators enable combinations and negation.